Register of the Herbert Hoover papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Unpublished Writings, 1944-1964
  - "The Ordeal of the American People"
    - 4th edition, 1961 July
      - Section III. "1939: The Year of Monstrous Evils for Mankind" [MO60], [MO63], [MO64] (Box-folder 32: 4-6)
      - Section IV. "The War Begins: Impacts on the United States" [MO61], [MO63], [MO64] (Box-folder 33: 1-5)
      - Section V. "The Beginning of the Greatest Disaster to Mankind since Genghis Khan" [MO63], [MO64] (Box-folder 33: 6-7)
      - Section VI. "The Road to War" [MO66], [MO63], [MO64] (Box-folder 34: 1-4)
      - Section VII. "Divergent Purposes of the Allied Leaders" [MO63] (Box-folder 34: 5-6)
      - Section VIII. "The March of Conferences" [MO70], [MO63], [MO64] (Box-folder 34: 7)
      - Section VIII. "The March of Conferences" [MO70], [MO63], [MO64] (cont.) (Box-folder 35: 1-3)
      - Section IX. "The March of Conferences (Continued)" [MO63], [MO64] (Box-folder 35: 4-5)
      - Section X. "The March of Conferences (Continued)" [MO63], [MO64] (Box-folder 35: 6-7)
    - 5th edition, 1961 September
      - Section I. "The Infiltration of Communism in the United States" [MO69], [MO101] (Box-folder 35: 8)
      - Section I. "The Infiltration of Communism in the United States" [MO69], [MO101] (Box-folder 36: 1-3)
      - Section II. "1938: Signs and Portents of a Second World War" [MO65], [MO101] (Box-folder 36: 4-5)
      - Section II. "1938: Signs and Portents of a Second World War" [MO65], [MO101] (cont.) (Box-folder 37: 1-2)
      - Section III. "1939: The Year of Monstrous Evils for Mankind" [MO101] (Box-folder 37: 3)
      - Section IV. "President Roosevelt's Policies under the Impact of the European War" [MO101] (Box-folder 37: 4)
      - Section V. "President Roosevelt's Opportunity to Make Lasting Peace in the World" [MO68], [MO101] (Box-folder 37: 5-7)
      - Section VI. "The Road to War" [MO67], [MO101] (Box-folder 38: 1-3)
      - Section VII. "The March of Conferences" [MO71], [MO101] (Box-folder 39: 1-2, Box-folder 38: 4-5)
      - Section VIII. "The March of Conferences (Continued)" [re Tehran Conference] [MO72], [MO73], [MO102] (Box-folder 39: 3-5)
      - Section VIII. "The March of Conferences (Continued)" [re Tehran Conference] [MO72], [MO73], [MO102] (cont.) (Box-folder 40: 1-4)
      - Section IX. "The March of Conferences (Continued)" [MO72], [MO102] (Box-folder 40: 5-6)
      - Section X. "The March of Conferences (Continued)" [re Yalta Conference] [MO74], [MO102] (Box-folder 41: 1-6)
      - Section XI. "The First Days of the Truman Administration" [MO75], [MO102] (Box-folder 42: 1-4)
      - Section XII. "The Potsdam Conference and After" [MO76], [MO102] (Box-folder 42: 5-6)
      - Section XII. "The Potsdam Conference and After" [MO76], [MO102] (cont.) (Box-folder 43: 1-2)
      - Section XIII. "An Era of Confusion in American Policies toward Russia" [MO102] (Box-folder 43: 3)
      - Section XIV. "An Appraisal of the March of Communism Seven Months after the War's End" [MO102] (Box-folder 43: 4)
      - Section XV. "Tragic Case Histories" [MO102] (Box-folder 43: 5)
      - "A Case History of Poland" (Box-folder 43: 6-8)
      - "A Case History of Poland" (cont.) (Box-folder 44: 1)
      - "A Case History of China" (Box-folder 44: 2-7)
  - "The Ordeal of the American People: Communist Infiltration into the Federal Government,", 1961 October (Box-folder 45: 1-4)
  - "Freedom Betrayed"
    - 6th edition, 1962 April
      - Section I. "The Communist Conspiracy in the United States" [MO104], [MO103], [MO107] (Box-folder 46: 1-3)
      - Section II. "1938: Signs and Portents of a Second World War" [MO104], [MO103], [MO107] (Box-folder 46: 4-6)
      - Section III. "1939: A Year of Monstrous Evils for Mankind" [MO104], [MO103], [MO107] (Box-folder 46: 7)
      - Section III. "1939: A Year of Monstrous Evils for Mankind" [MO104], [MO103], [MO107] (contd.) (Box-folder 47: 1-2)
      - Section IV. "President Roosevelt's Policies under the Impact of the European War" [MO104], [MO103], [MO107] (Box-folder 47: 3-5)
      - Section V. "The Opportunity to Make Lasting Peace in the World Came to Franklin Roosevelt" [MO105], [MO103], [MO107] (Box-folder 47: 6-8)
      - Section VI. "The Road to War" [MO105], [MO103], [MO107] (Box-folder 48: 1-3)
      - Section VII. "The March of Conferences" [MO105], [MO103], [MO107], [MO106] (Box-folder 48: 4-5)
      - Section VII. "The March of Conferences" [MO105], [MO103], [MO107], [MO106] (contd.) (Box-folder 49: 1-2)
      - Section VIII. "The March of Conferences" [re Tehran Conference] [MO106], [MO103], [MO108] (Box-folder 49: 3-6)
      - Section IX. "The March of Conferences" [MO106], [MO103], [MO108] (Box-folder 50: 1-3)
      - Section X. "The March of Conferences" [re Yalta Conference] [MO106], [MO103], [MO108] (Box-folder 50: 4-6)
      - Section XI. "The First Days of the Truman Administration" [MO106] (Box-folder 50: 7-8)
      - Section XII. "The Preservation of Lasting Peace" [MO106] (Box-folder 50: 9)
      - Section XIII. "The Potsdam Conference and After" [MO106] (Box-folder 50: 10)
      - Section XIV. Untitled [MO106] (Box-folder 50: 11)
      - Section XV. "A Case History of Poland" [MO106] (Box-folder 51: 1-2)
      - Section XVI. "The Decline and Fall of Free China" (Box-folder 51: 3-5)
      - "Vengeance Comes to Germany" (Box-folder 51: 6)
    - 7th edition, 1962 May
      - Section I. "The Communist Conspiracy in the United States" [MO111], [MO109], [MO112] (Box-folder 51: 7)
      - Section I. "The Communist Conspiracy in the United States" [MO111], [MO109], [MO112] (contd.) (Box-folder 52: 1-3)
      - Section II. "1938: Signs and Portents of a Second World War" [MO111], [MO109], [MO112] (Box-folder 52: 4-7)
      - Section III. "1939: A Year of Monstrous Evils for Mankind" [MO111], [MO109], [MO112] (Box-folder 53: 1-4)
      - Section IV. "The Impact of War on the American People" [MO111], [MO109], [MO112] (Box-folder 53: 5-8)
      - Section V. "The Opportunity to Make Lasting Peace in the World Came to Franklin Roosevelt" [MO111], [MO109], [MO112] (Box-folder 53: 9-12)
      - Section VI. "Brainwashing the American People" [MO111], [MO109], [MO112] (Box-folder 53: 13)
      - Section VI. "Brainwashing the American People" [MO111], [MO109], [MO112] (contd.) (Box-folder 54: 1-3)
      - Section VII. "Marching on the Road to War" [MO111], [MO109], [MO112] (Box-folder 54: 4-7)
      - Section VIII. "The March of Conferences" [MO111], [MO110], [MO112] (Box-folder 54: 8-11)
      - Section IX. "The March of Conferences" [MO111], [MO110], [MO112] (Box-folder 54: 12-15)
      - Section X. "The Tehran-Cairo Conferences" [MO111], [MO110], [MO112] (Box-folder 54: 16)
      - Section X. "The Tehran-Cairo Conferences" [MO111], [MO110], [MO112] (contd.) (Box-folder 55: 1-3)
      - Section XI. "The March of Conferences" [MO111], [MO110], [MO112] (Box-folder 55: 4-7)
      - Section XII. "The March of Conferences" [re Yalta Conference] [MO111], [MO110], [MO112] (Box-folder 55: 8-11)
      - Section XIII. "The First Days of the Truman Administration" [MO111], [MO110], [MO112] (Box-folder 56: 1-4)
      - Section XIV. "The Preservation of Lasting Peace" [MO111], [MO110], [MO112] (Box-folder 56: 5-8)
      - Section XV. "The Potsdam Conference and After" [MO111], [MO110], [MO112] (Box-folder 56: 9-12)
      - Section XVI. "The Era of Inconsistent American Relations with the Communists" [MO111], [MO110], [MO112] (Box-folder 56: 13-16)
      - Section XVII. "Vengeance Comes to Germany" (Box-folder 56: 17)
      - Section XVIII. "The Case History of Poland" (Box-folder 56: 18)
      - Section XVIII. "The Case History of Poland" (contd.) (Box-folder 57: 1-2)
      - Section XIX. "The Decline and Fall of Free China" (Box-folder 57: 3-4)
      - Section XIX. "The Decline and Fall of Free China" (contd.) (Box-folder 58: 1)
    - 8th edition, 1962 July
      - Section I. "The Communist Conspiracy in the United States" [MO113], [MO114] (Box-folder 58: 2-3)
      - Section II. "I Make an Appraisal of the Advance of Communism and Fascism in 1938" [MO113], [MO114], [MO115] (Box-folder 58: 4-6)
      - Section III. "1939: A Year of Monstrous Evils for Mankind" [MO113], [MO114], [MO115] (Box-folder 59: 1-3)
      - Section IV. "The Impact of War on the American People" [MO113], [MO114], [MO115] (Box-folder 59: 4-6)
    - 9th edition, 1962 September
      - Section I. "The Greatest Intellectual Plague Which Has Come to Mankind" [MO117], [MO116] (Box-folder 59: 7-8)
      - Section II. "I Make an Appraisal of the Advance of Communism and Fascism in 1938" [MO117] (Box-folder 59: 9)
      - Section III. "1939: A Year of Monstrous Evils for Mankind" [MO117] (Box-folder 59: 10)
      - Section IV. "The Impact of War on the American People" [MO117] (Box-folder 60: 1)
      - Section V. "The Opportunity to Make Lasting Peace in the World Came to Franklin Roosevelt" [MO117] (Box-folder 60: 2)
      - Section VI. "Brainwashing the American People" [MO117] (Box-folder 60: 3)
      - Section VII. "The Road to War" [MO117] (Box-folder 60: 4)
    - 10th edition, 1962 December
      - Introduction. "The Backgrounds of this Memoir" [MO118], [MO119], [MO120] (Box-folder 60: 5-8)
      - Section I. "The Greatest Intellectual Plague Which Has Come to Mankind" [MO116], [MO118], [MO119], [MO120] (Box-folder 60: 9-13)
      - Section II. "I Make an Appraisal of the Forces Moving among Nations in 1938" [MO118], [MO119], [MO120] (Box-folder 61: 1-4)
      - Section III. "1939: A Year of Monstrous Evils for Mankind" [MO118], [MO119], [MO120] (Box-folder 61: 5-8)
      - Section IV. "A Revolution in American Foreign Policies" [MO118], [MO119], [MO120] (Box-folder 61: 9)
      - Section IV. "A Revolution in American Foreign Policies" [MO118], [MO119], [MO120] (contd.) (Box-folder 62: 1-3)
      - Section V. "Hitler Turns His Might against Communist Russia" [MO118], [MO119], [MO120] (Box-folder 62: 4-7)
      - Section VI. "Brainwashing the American People" [MO118], [MO119], [MO120] (Box-folder 62: 8-11)
      - Section VII. "The Road to War" [MO118], [MO119], [MO120] (Box-folder 62: 12-14)
      - Section VII. "The Road to War" [MO118], [MO119], [MO120] (contd.) (Box-folder 63: 1)
      - Section VIII. "The March of Conferences" (Box-folder 63: 2)
      - Section IX. "The March of Conferences" (Box-folder 63: 3)
      - Section X. "The Tehran-Cairo Conferences" (Box-folder 63: 4)
      - Section XI. "The March of Conferences" (Box-folder 63: 5)
      - Section XII. "The Yalta Conference, February 4 to 11, 1945" (Box-folder 63: 6)
      - Section XIII. "The Decline and Fall of the Atlantic Charter" (Box-folder 63: 7)
      - Section XIV. "The First Days of the Truman Administration" (Box-folder 63: 8)
      - Section XV. "The Potsdam Conference and After" (Box-folder 63: 9)
    - Z edition, 1963 March
      - Introduction (Box-folder 64: 1-3)
      - Section I. "Free Men's Greatest Moral and Intellectual Plague" (Box-folder 64: 4-7)
      - Section II. "I Make an Appraisal of the Forces Moving among Nations in 1938" (Box-folder 64: 8-11)
      - Section III. "A Revolution in American Foreign Policies" (Box-folder 64: 12)
      - Section III. "A Revolution in American Foreign Policies" (contd.) (Box-folder 65: 1-3)
      - Section IV. "1939: In Europe, a Year of Monstrous Evils for Mankind" (Box-folder 65: 4-7)
      - Section V. "The Communist-Nazi Conquest of Europe" (Box-folder 65: 8-11)
      - Section VI. "More American Action: Stronger than Words but Less than War" (Box-folder 65: 12-15)
      - Section VII. "Brainwashing the American People" (Box-folder 65: 16-18)
      - Section VIII. "The Continued Revolution in American Foreign Policies" (Box-folder 66: 1-3)
      - Section IX. "Hitler Turns His Might against Communist Russia" (Box-folder 66: 4-7)
      - Section X. "The Road to War" (Box-folder 66: 8-10)
      - Section XI. "The March of Conferences" (Box-folder 67: 1-2)
      - Section XII. "The March of Conferences, 1943" (Box-folder 67: 3-4)
      - Section XIII. "The March of Conferences: The Tehran-Cairo Conferences, November-December 1943" (Box-folder 67: 5-6)
      - Section XIV. "The March of Conferences" (Box-folder 67: 7-8)
      - Section XV. "The March of Conferences: The Yalta Conference, February 4-11, 1945" (Box-folder 68: 1)
      - Section XVI. "The Rise, Decline and Fall of the Atlantic Charter" (Box-folder 68: 2-3)
      - Section XVII. "The First Days of the Truman Administration" (Box-folder 68: 4-5)
      - Section XVIII. "The Potsdam Conference and After" (Box-folder 68: 6-7)
      - Volume III. "A Step-by-Step History of Poland" (Box-folder 68: 8-9)
      - Volume III. "A Step-by-Step History of Poland" (contd.) (Box-folder 69: 1-4)
      - Volume III. "The Case History of Korea" (Box-folder 69: 5)
      - Volume III. "The Case History of Korea" (contd.) (Box-folder 70: 1-3)
      - "The Decline and Fall of Free China: A Case History" (Box-folder 70: 4-6)
      - "The Decline and Fall of Free China: A Case History" (contd.) (Box-folder 71: 1-2)
    - Z+H edition, 1963 July version
      - Introduction (Box-folder 71: 3-5)
      - Section I. "A Great Intellectual and Moral Plague Comes to Free Men" (Box-folder 71: 6-8)
      - Section II. "I Make an Appraisal of the Forces Moving among Nations in 1938" (Box-folder 71: 9-11)
      - Section III. "A Revolution in American Foreign Policies" (Box-folder 72: 1-3)
      - Section IV. "1939: In Europe, a Year of Monstrous Evils for Mankind" (Box-folder 72: 4-6)
      - Section V. "The Communist-Nazi Conquest of Europe" (Box-folder 72: 7-9)
      - Section VI. "More American Action: Stronger than Words but Less than War" (Box-folder 72: 10-12)
      - Section VII. "Brainwashing the American People" (Box-folder 72: 13-15)
      - Section VIII. "The Revolution in American Foreign Policies Continued" (Box-folder 72: 16-18)
      - Section IX. "The Opportunity to Make Lasting Peace Came to Franklin Roosevelt" (Box-folder 72: 19-21)
      - Section X. "The Road to War" (Box-folder 73: 1-3)
      - Section XI. "The March of Conferences" (Box-folder 73: 4)
      - Section XII. "The March of Conferences" (Box-folder 73: 5)
      - Section XIII. "The March of Conferences: The Tehran-Cairo Conferences, November-December 1943" (Box-folder 73: 6)
      - Section XIV. "The March of Conferences" (Box-folder 73: 7)
      - Section XV. "The March of Conferences: The Yalta Conference, February 4-11, 1945" (Box-folder 73: 8)
      - Section XVI. "The Rise, Decline and Fall of the Atlantic Charter" (Box-folder 73: 9)
      - Section XVII. "The First Days of the Truman Administration" (Box-folder 73: 10)
      - Section XVIII. "The March of Conferences: The Potsdam Conference and After" (Box-folder 74: 1)
    - Z+H edition, 1963 September version
      - Introduction (Box-folder 74: 2-4)
      - Section I. "A Great Intellectual and Moral Plague Comes to Free Men" (Box-folder 74: 5-8)
      - Section II. "I Make an Appraisal of the Forces Moving among Nations in 1938" (Box-folder 75: 9-12)
      - Section III. "A Revolution in American Foreign Policies" (Box-folder 75: 1-4)
      - Section IV. "1939: In Europe, a Year of Monstrous Evils for Mankind" (Box-folder 75: 5-8)
      - Section V. "The Communist-Nazi Conquest of Europe" (Box-folder 75: 9-12)
      - Section VI. "More American Action: Stronger than Words, but Less than War" (Box-folder 75: 13-16)
      - Section VII. "Brainwashing the American People" (Box-folder 75: 17-20)
      - Section VIII. "The Revolution in American Foreign Policies Continued" (Box-folder 75: 21-24)
      - Section IX. "The Opportunity to Make Lasting Peace Comes to Franklin Roosevelt" (Box-folder 76: 1-4)
      - Section X. "The Road to War" (Box-folder 76: 5-8)
      - Bound set
        - Sections I-V (Box-folder 76: 9)
        - Sections VI-X (Box-folder 77: 1)
        - Sections XI-XIV (Box-folder 77: 2)
        - Sections XV-XVIII (Box-folder 77: 3)
    - Z+H edition, 1964 March version
      - Section XI. "The March of Conferences" (Box-folder 77: 4)
      - Section XII. "The March of Conferences" (Box-folder 77: 5)
      - Section XIII. "The March of Conferences: The Tehran-Cairo Conferences, November-December 1943" (Box-folder 78: 1)
      - Section XIV. "The March of Conferences" (Box-folder 78: 2)
      - Section XV. "The March of Conferences: The Yalta Conference, February 4-11, 1945" (Box-folder 78: 3)
      - Section XVI. "The Rise, Decline and Fall of the Atlantic Charter" (Box-folder 78: 4)
      - Section XVII. "The First Days of the Truman Administration" (Box-folder 78: 5)
      - Section XVIII. "The March of Conferences: The Potsdam Conference and After" (Box-folder 78: 6)
    - Z+H edition, 1964 December version
      - Section I. "The Infiltration of Communism in the United States" (Box-folder 79: 1-10)
      - Section I. "The Infiltration of Communism in the United States" (contd.) (Box-folder 80: 1)
      - Section II. "1938: Signs and Portents of a Second World War" (Box-folder 80: 2-10)
      - Section II. "1938: Signs and Portents of a Second World War" (contd.) (Box-folder 81: 1-2)
      - Section III. "A Revolution in American Foreign Policies" (Box-folder 81: 3-13)
      - Section IV. "1939: In Europe, a Year of Monstrous Evils for Mankind" (Box-folder 81: 14-21)
      - Section IV. "1939: In Europe, a Year of Monstrous Evils for Mankind" (contd.) (Box-folder 82: 1-3)
      - Section V. "The Communist-Nazi Conquest of Europe" (Box-folder 82: 4-8)
      - Section VI. "More American Action: Stronger than Words, but Less than War" (Box-folder 82: 9-13)
      - Section VII. "Brainwashing the American People" (Box-folder 82: 14-18)
      - Section VIII. "The Revolution in American Foreign Policies Continued" (Box-folder 82: 19-23)
      - Section IX. "The Opportunity to Make Lasting Peace Comes to Franklin Roosevelt" (Box-folder 83: 1-5)
      - Section X. "The Road to War" (Box-folder 83: 6-9)
      - Section XI. "The March of Conferences" (Box-folder 83: 10-12)
      - Section XI. "The March of Conferences" (contd.) (Box-folder 84: 1-2)
      - Section XII. "The March of Conferences" (Box-folder 84: 3-7)
      - Section XIII. "The March of Conferences: The Tehran-Cairo Conferences, November-December 1943" (Box-folder 84: 8-12)
      - Section XIV. "The March of Conferences" (Box-folder 85: 1-5)
      - Section XV. "The March of Conferences: The Yalta Conference, February 4 to February 11, 1945" (Box-folder 85: 6-10)
      - Section XVI. "The Rise, Decline and Fall of the Atlantic Charter" (Box-folder 85: 11-15)
      - Section XVII. "The First Days of the Truman Administration" (Box-folder 85: 16-20)
      - Section XVIII. "The March of Conferences: The Potsdam Conference and After" (Box-folder 86: 1-5)
    - Various and unknown versions (Box-folder 86: 6-7)
      Miscellaneous, duplicate and discarded drafts; fragments; corrections; notes.
    - Various and unknown versions (contd.) (Box-folder 87: 1-3)
- Correspondence, 1953-1978
  Correspondence relating to composition and publication of unpublished writings
  - General, 1953-1965 (Box-folder 95: 1)
  - Akmentins, Osvalds, 1963 (Box-folder 95: 2)
  - Berlin, Richard E., 1963 (Box-folder 95: 3)
  - Clark, Mark W., 1962 (Box-folder 95: 4)
  - Cole, Albert, 1963 (Box-folder 95: 5)
  - Dennen, Leon, 1963 (Box-folder 95: 6)
  - Dozer, Donald M., 1961 (Box-folder 95: 7)
  - Edison, Charles, 1963 (Box-folder 95: 8)
  - Epstein, Julius, 1964 (Box-folder 95: 9)
  - Galpin, Perrin C., 1963 (Box-folder 95: 10)
  - Grimm, Peter, 1963 (Box-folder 95: 11)
  - Henle, Ray, 1963 (Box-folder 95: 12)
  - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, 1962-1978 (Box-folder 95: 13)
    Includes Rita R. Campbell, W. Glenn Campbell, Milorad Drachkovitch, Witold S. Sworakowski, and Eugene Wu
  - Kaltenborn, H. V., 1963 (Box-folder 95: 14)
  - McCloy, John J., 1963 (Box-folder 95: 15)
  - MacNeil, Neil, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 95: 16)
  - McSherry, J. E., 1965 (Box-folder 95: 17)
  - Mullendore, William C., 1963 (Box-folder 95: 18)
  - Nichols, William L., 1963 (Box-folder 95: 19)
  - St. John, Fordyce B., 1963 (Box-folder 95: 20)
  - Schullinger, Rudolph N., 1962 (Box-folder 95: 21)
  - Shoemaker, P. M., 1963 (Box-folder 95: 22)
  - Sokolsky, George E., 1953-1962 (Box-folder 95: 23)
  - Strauss, Lewis L, 1963 (Box-folder 95: 24)
  - Thompson, Glenn, 1962 (Box-folder 95: 25)
  - Wallace, DeWitt, 1963 (Box-folder 95: 26)
  - Wedemeyer, Albert C., 1963 (Box-folder 95: 27)
  - White, William L., 1962-1964 (Box-folder 95: 28)
- New Deal Subject File, 1932-1960
  Notes, printed matter, and typed excerpts from printed sources, used as research material for unpublished writings on the New Deal. Includes material collected for Hoover by Lawrence Sullivan.
  - Agriculture, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 95: 29-30)
    Contains notes, U.S. Department of Agriculture press releases, speeches by Henry A. Wallace, pamphlets, clippings, and typed excerpts from printed sources.
  - American Mercury, serial issues, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 96: 1-2)
  - Bureaucracy, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 96: 3)
    Notes, clippings, and typed excerpts from speeches by Franklin D. Roosevelt and other public sources.
  - Business-Regulation by government, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 96: 4)
    Notes, clippings, statistical data, and typed excerpts from speeches by New Deal officials and printed sources.
  - Censorship clippings, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 96: 5)
  - Chronology
    Notes, clippings, and Congressional Record excerpts relating mainly to New Deal legislation.
    - 1933 March (Box-folder 96: 6)
    - 1933 April (Box-folder 97: 1)
    - 1934 September (Box-folder 97: 2)
  - Civilian Conservation Corps, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 97: 3)
    Notes, clippings, governmental press releases and report, and typed excerpts from public sources.
  - Communism-Analogies with New Deal, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 97: 4)
    Notes, synopses of books, typed excerpts from printed sources, letter by Ralph H. Lutz, and printed articles.
  - Conflicts of New Deal policies, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 97: 5)
    Notes, clippings, and typed excerpts from public sources.
  - Currency and credit (Box-folder 97: 6)
    Notes, clippings, pamphlets, and typed excerpts from public sources, 1933-1940. Includes An Appraisal of the Monetary Policies of Our Federal Government; Documents and Statements Pertaining to the Banking Emergency; Gold and Armageddon; The Origins of the Banking Panic of March 4, 1933; Recent Literature on the Gold Problem.
  - Economic statistics, 1934 (Box-folder 97: 7)
    Notes, clippings, and statistical data.
  - Economy, 1933-1936 (Box-folder 97: 8)
    Notes, U.S. Department of Commerce press release, and pamphlets. Includes The Deserted Village; Principles of American Enterprise; What Is Industry?; What Must We Do to Save Our Economic System?; Who Shares America's Wealth?
  - Elections--1934, clippings (Box-folder 97: 9)
  - Evaluations of New Deal, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 98: 1)
    Newspaper article by Winston Churchill and pamphlets. Includes The Genesis of the "New Deal" with Some Revelations; The New Deal: An Impartial History of the Roosevelt Administration; On the Road to Moscow; Promise and Performance: The Administration of Franklin D. Roosevelt Reveals Itself.
  - Fascism-Analogies with New Deal, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 98: 2)
    Notes, clippings, printed articles, and typed excerpts from printed sources.
  - Foreign trade, circa 1933-1934 (Box-folder 98: 3)
    Clippings and typed excerpts from printed sources.
  - Hearst, William Randolph, clippings, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 98: 4)
  - Home loans, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 98: 5)
    Notes, Federal Home Loan Bank Board press releases, clippings, and typed excerpts from printed sources, 1933-1934.
  - Ideology (general), 1935-1936 (Box-folder 98: 6)